TYLER SIMEONE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

|--|

in /in/tylersimeone

? /tyler-simeone

(615)-715-3944

ABOUT ME

I became aware of programming at a young age as my dad has been a programmer since the '80s. However, it wasn't until I took an online course that I realized programming was something that I could really enjoy doing as a career. I love working in teams and solving problems to achieve goals, which is another reason I enjoy coding.

MTB CONNECT

- Web Application that allows users to search mountain bike trails by zip code and build a network of mountain biking friends that ride similar trails.
- I built this front-end app in three
 weeks using React.js with React State
 and React Hooks for displaying data
 and handling the user interface. CSS
 and Material UI for styling. As well as
 JSON Server with fetch requests for
 data storage and manipulation.
- https://github.com/tylersimeone/MTB-Connect

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full-stack Web Development

Columbia State Community College AS

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Developer

Nashville Software School

AUG 2019 - PRESENT

Intensive full-time, full-stack software development course with an emphasis on individual and team-based projects.

Three months of remote learning and group project experience.

TECH STACK:

- Built single page web applications using JavaScript, React, HTML and CSS
- Utilized Git and GitHub for version control and issue tracking
- Utilized React State, Hooks, and Props to render data to the page and handle the user interface
- Utilized RESTful API architecture for all applications built

REACT NUTSHELL - (Group Project)

- Built app with a team of three
- Multi-functional site that includes news articles, local events, restaurants, and task lists
- I built the task components that allow the user to perform CRUD operations on their task list using React.js, JSON Server, Reactstrap, and GitHub
- https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-38/react-nutshell-pyroclastic-thunder-nerds

WORK EXPERIENCE

Franklin Water Store - Sales Associate

JUL 2018 - JUL 2019

Small business focused on producing and selling alkaline drinking water

• Worked with a small team to inform customers about the benefits of alkaline water and water ionizing machines

Delivery Dudes - Delivery Driver

APR 2015 - MAY 2018

- Worked at the DD headquarters where I used a web application to fulfill online and phone orders
- Delivery driver where I was responsible for constant communication with the HQ, inspecting customer orders from restaurants, and executing a timely delivery